Derrick Antoney

Nairobi, Kenya | +254758931761 | Porfoliowebsite | Email | Linkedin | Github | Credly | X

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Effective listener/communicator and fast diligent learner that is hungry for knowledge and keeping up-to-date with current technology. Ample experience in full-stack development, delivering well-documented, tested, and operable code. Efficient in collaborating and communicating new ideas and opinions.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

The Odin ProjectHTML, CSS, Javascript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React Js, Node Js, Express JsNovember 2022Freecodecamp.org - Responsive Web DevelopmentHTML, CSS, JavascriptSeptember 2022IBM Cognitive Class - Data SciencePython, SQL DatabasesJanuary 2022Google - Foundations of User Experience DesignUX/UI DesignDecember 2022

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Typescript/Javascript, Python, Ruby, SQL (Postgres, MySQL), HTML, JSON, SCSS/CSS, Sass

Frameworks/Libraries: React, React Native, NextJS, Node.js, Daisy UI, Next UI, Material UI, Django, ExpressJS, Ruby on Rails

DevOps and API Tools: CI/CD, Git, Docker, Github, Kubernetes, Vercel, Azure DevOps, Swagger, Postman

Cloud and Security Tools: IBM Cloud, Azure Cloud, Linux (Configuring and Managing)

Others: Agile (Scrum/Kanban), NOSQL (Mongo DB), Mongoose, Sanity, NPM, Stripe Js, Debugging

EXPERIENCE

Staarab Agency - Hybrid | Fullstack Developer, Nairobi, Kenya

January 2021 -Present

- Leveraging responsive web development for various devices leading to 60% increase in uptake.
- Providing support for different intergrations like mailing, payments and SEO as per various client needs.
- Utilizing redux for state management and database querying.
- Managing the end-to-end life cycle for production of software and applications.
- Modifying and testing changes to previously developed programs.

Frontend Developer - Remote | Savup, San Mateo, California

February 2023 – October 2023

- Refactoring existing components and logic to improve readability, accessibility and performance.
- Overhauling existing components and widgets and redeveloping to reflect latest UX/UI designs.
- Utilizing Dart and Flutter for development and Android Studio for simulation.
- Guiding design and development of components by utilizing customer survey and feedback.
- Conducting competitive audits, usability studies, drawing user journey maps and identifying user pain points that impede app usage.

Backend Developer - Remote | *FarmConnect*, *Kampala Uganda*

October 2023 – February 2024

- Developing REST APIs using Django RESTframework for the desired implementation patterns.
- Utilizing MVC design architecture for application functionality development.
- Implementing passwordless authentication thereby increasing uptake among users.
- Customizing API security using OAUTH and JWT.
- Playing team role through collaboration with UX design team, product manager and CTO for effective project delivery.

EDUCATION

Jomo Kenyatta University WorldQuant University **BSc in Geomatic Engineering and GIS** | Nairobi, Kenya. **Applied Data Science Certificate** | New Orleans, LA - Online

September 2017 – December 2022 November 2022 – March 2023

PROJECTS

Socialmui | React Js., Redux, NPM, Material UI, Supabase

March 2024

- Socialmui provide much needed bonding among friends and families.
- Old friends can catch up here distance not withstanding. Features include, photo, text and video sharing.

<u>Customer Dashboard</u> | NextJs, ReactJs, Typescript, PostgresSQL, Server Actions, Next-SEO, Next Auth, Tailwind CSS January 2024

Provides detailed information about customers. Invoices can be created for customers.

Cooperate Website | ReactJs, Vite, ESLint, Framer Motion, SCSS, EmailJs,

April 2024

- Cooperate website for clients onboarding.